A Guide to the China Medical Board, Inc. records, RG 1 FA065
Rockefeller Archive Center
China Medical Board, Inc. records, RG 1
1914-1971, 2005-2012
1914-1971
Rockefeller Archive Center
China Medical Board of New York
Rockefeller Foundation. China Medical Board
Peking Union Medical College
Rockefeller Foundation
China Medical Board (U.S)
FA065
94.24 Cubic Feet
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged alphabetically, as used by the office staff of the CMB, Inc. The title of the file can be the name of a person, an office, an organization or a subject. The office personnel gave a mark-up to each piece of correspondence to indicate where a particular letter or report would be filed. Mark-ups indicate two things: first, under what file the item should be placed, and second, whether the item was written by, sent to or about a specific person or organization. For example: Health Station - Chu, C. K. Health Station is the file heading and the name Chu shows the item to be either written by, sent to or about Mr. Chu). In the following, when a mark-up is referred to, it will mean the second part, by, to or about X. Where a mark-up has appeared in a file, it has been listed following the main entry to help locate specific material. For instance, Mr. Greene's letters might have been scattered by topic and not grouped in his file. His name, therefore, will appear after many topic headings to indicate that the material by, to or about him is located in that file.
If, after the file heading, there are inclusive dates, and the mark-ups are listed without dates, this means that the file is arranged chronologically. If, after the file heading, there are no dates, the mark-ups will have inclusive dates following them. This indicates that the file is arranged alphabetically by person and then chronologically within each person's section. If, however, inclusive dates follow both the file heading and the mark-up, this means that there is first a general section, where no person or organization was listed after the file heading and this is arranged chronologically. The remainder of the file will then be arranged alphabetically by mark-up and chronologically within each individual section.
Example - Chronological Listing
Field Studies - Anthropology, 1920-1945: Director; Greene; Houghton; Newsweek Magazine; Pei; Weidenreich
Example - Alphabetical Listing
Neurology - Staff: Agos, I. H., 1922-1925; Alexander, L. 1932-1934; Burwell, A., 1924-1925; Chao, Pao-hsun, 1949; Chao, Yi-cheng, 1932; Cheng, (Yu-lin) Leslie, 1927
A series of China Medical Board, Inc. photographs follows the folder listing.
Biographical/Historical note
The China Medical Board, Inc. traces its origin to the unincorporated China Medical Board, which was created in 1914 as a division of the Rockefeller Foundation to care for the developing interests of the foundation in China (see Rockefeller Foundation Archives, Record Group 4). In 1915, the Rockefeller Foundation purchased and assumed support of the Union Medical College in Peking, which had been founded in 1906 by a group of Protestant missionaries. The institution was renamed the Peking Union Medical College (at times referred to as the Peiping Union Medical College). Its reconstruction, development and support gradually became the primary, though not the exclusive, interest of the China Medical Board. At formal dedication ceremonies held in Peking in 1921, the objectives of the Peking Union Medical College (PUMC) were set forth in a speech delivered by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. These can be summarized as follows:
1. To develop in China a medical school and hospital comparable with that of the leading institutions of Western civilization and to offer thorough training in scientific medicine.
2. To stimulate the creation of similar institutions in various parts of China.
3. To provide graduate instruction in the form of short courses in subjects for which the need is great.
4. To prosecute research, for the influence it may exert upon standards and methods of medical education, the training of teachers and leaders, and the solution of problems of disease in China.
5. To permeate the work of the institution with the finest idealism and to interpret to China the best of the West, not only in medical science but in mental development and spiritual culture.
6. To make permanent on Chinese soil the best in scientific medicine that the world can offer, with the realization that what it may have to offer will be of little avail to the Chinese people until it is taken over by them and becomes a part of the national life. Toward this end, to create in the future a faculty of whom most, if not all, are Chinese and a Board of Trustees similarly constituted.
In 1928, the China Medical Board was incorporated under the Membership Corporations Law of the State of New York. Its certificate of incorporation provided that "the purposes of which it is formed are exclusively charitable, educational and scientific and are to extend financial support to the Peking Union Medical College and/or like institutions in the Far East or in the United States of America." The Rockefeller Foundation transferred to the new organization the ownership of the land and buildings occupied by the Peking Union Medical College and endowed it with the sum of $12,000,000, agreeing to provide, from time to time, additional grants toward the college budget. Until the outbreak of the war with Japan in 1941, the CMB, Inc. devoted its entire income to the support of the College.
While the Peking Union Medical College (PUMC) was occupied by the Japanese, the CMB, Inc. carried on a program of aid to medical institutions in unoccupied China. At the same time, it assisted undergraduate students of the College to continue their studies elsewhere and helped maintain the College nursing school in Chengtu.
The Peking Union Medical College (PUMC) was recovered from the Japanese at the close of the war, but was then used as the Executive Headquarters of General Marshall's Peace Commission until April 1947. At this time the CMB, Inc. resumed its annual grant to the Peking Union Medical College (PUMC). By May 1948, the medical school, nursing school and the hospital were once again in operation, though not at the same level as before the war. In January 1951 the Peking Union Medical College was nationalized by the People's Republic of China.
Since funds could no longer be sent to the Peking Union Medical College (PUMC) or to the mainland, the China Medical Board, Inc. embarked on a new program and enlarged its field within the geographical limits permitted by its charter. Under this program, the CMB, Inc. provides assistance to medical, public health and nursing schools in many Far Eastern countries, and to a lesser degree, to medical, public health and nursing schools in the United States.
Scope and Contents note
The China Medical Board, Inc. Collection, 1914-1971, consists almost exclusively of material dealing with the Peking Union Medical College (PUMC), 1918-1951. The Peking Union Medical College (PUMC) appears to have sent to its financial supporters, first the China Medical Board and then the China Medical Board, Inc., much of its correspondence, memos and reports, to keep those in New York informed as to what was going on in China. As the ownership of the buildings and grounds of the Peking Union Medical College (PUMC) was transferred from the CMB to the CMB, Inc., many records were also transferred. This accounts for many pre-1928 documents found in the files.
Headings that may be of interest to the researcher: Administrative Council China Medical Board - Annual Report - Diary - History China Medical Board, Inc. - Annual Report Departments, listed by name Anatomy Bacteriology Biochemistry Biology Chemistry Dentistry Dermatology Dietary Field Studies Gynecology Health Station Hospital Library Medicine Neurology Nurses Ophthalmology Otology Parasitology Pathology Pediatrics Pharmacology Pharmacy Physics Physiology Radiology Religion Surgery Director - PUMC - Annual Report Documents of Record Eggleston, M. K. - Interviews Greene, R. S. - Diary - Interviews Governing Council Houghton, H. S. - Diary Peking Union Medical College - History Political Situation Publications - Weekly Calendar/News Bulletin Rockefeller Foundation Trustees - Minutes
Photographs can be found in the series that follows the folder listing.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IV 2B 09
Related Archival Materials note
For other related material, the reader should see the Rockefeller Foundation Archives, especially:
Record Group 1.1 - Projects
Series 100 - International
China Medical Board, Inc. folders, 1928-1953
Record Group 4 - The China Medical Board
Record Group 7 - Treasurer's Office
Record Group 8 - Comptroller's Office
Arrangement
Box #164 was not used.
General
C.M.B., Inc. - P.U.M.C. Records
China Medical Board Inc. Index
A card index to the CMB Inc records, arranged in 2 series of index cards, is available for researcher use:
1. The CMB Inc. Minutes Index provides indexing to minutes found box P 3 of the CMB records. Referenced minutes are indicated by a 5-digit number, formatted as a 2-digit year and 3-digit page-number, on the right edge of the cards. For example: "35123" = 1935 Minutes, page #123. The CMB Inc. Minutes index is located in drawers 9-10 of the 72-drawer cabinet next to the RAC's reading room.
2. The CMB Inc. Main Index provides indexing to the CMB's subject files. CMB files are indicated on the cards by the file titles (not index numbers). The CMB Main Index is located in drawers 11-17 of the 72-drawer cabinet next to the RAC's reading room.
Medical education; Medical libraries; Midwives; Nursing; Radiology; Pharmaceutical services; Bacteriology; Public health; China -- Politics and government; World War II; Surgery; Religion; Bacteria; China; Education, Nursing
- Aca-Acc (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Academia Sinica, 1932-1936 (Fu Ssu-nien, 1935; Ting, V. K., 1935-1936); Accountant - Greene, 1923; Accounting System - Kirk, 1922
- Accounts (Ap-Go) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  General, 1927-1947; Appropriations, 1935, 1942; Ballou, 1941; Bradfield, 1941; Chase National Bank, 1941; Comptroller, 1928-1949; Director, 1941; Embree, 1922; Exchange Reserve Fund, 1929-1938 (Director; Greene; Myers; Rockefeller, J. D. 3rd); Goodrich, 1925
- Accounts - Greene, R. S., 1917-1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Accounts - Greene, R. S., January-August 1929 (Box 1A, Folder 4)
- Accounts - Greene, R. S., September-December 1929 (Box 1A, Folder 5)
- Accounts - Greene, R. S., January-August 1930 (Box 1A, Folder 6)
- Accounts - Greene, R. S., September-December 1930 (Box 1A, Folder 7)
- Accounts - Greene, R. S., January-September 1931 (Box 1A, Folder 8)
- Accounts - Greene, R. S., October-December 1931 (Box 1A, Folder 9)
- Accounts - Greene, R. S., January-September 1932 (Box 1A, Folder 10)
- Accounts - Greene, R. S., October 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Accounts - Greene, R. S., October 1932 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Accounts - Greene, R. S., October 1935 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Accounts (Gr-Ho) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Gregg, 1934; Hogg, J. S., 1920-1925
- Accounts - Houghton, H. S., 1918-1934 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Accounts (K-P) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Kenzel, 1929; Mao, 1928; Memo, 1947-195; Myers, L. G., 1928-1931; Paris Office - Letort, 1933-1939; Pearce, 1929
- Accounts - Peking Stock, 1921-1947 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Comptroller; Dashiell; Director; Goodrich; Greene; Hogg; Houghton; Loucks; Lowe, Bingham & Mathews; Resident Director; Squires & Co.
- Accounts - Reserve Fund, 1928-1938 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  General; Bowen, T.; Comptroller; Director; Greene, R. S.; Houghton; Kenzel; Myers; Pearce; Robinson; Rockefeller, J. D. 3rd; Squire & Co.
- Accounts (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Resident Director, 1926-1927; Revolving Fund, 1940, 1961-1964
- Accounts - Retirement Savings, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 19A)
  Comptroller; Memos
- Accreditation, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 19B)
- Administrative Board Minutes, 1916-October 1919 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Administrative Board Minutes, December 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Administrative Board Minutes - Exhibits - Documents of Record, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Administrative Council Minutes - Index, 1921-1937 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Administrative Council Minutes, 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 23A)
- Administrative Council Minutes, 1922-1924 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Administrative Council Minutes, 1924-1925 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Administrative Council Minutes, 1925-1928 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Administrative Council Minutes, 1928-1933 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Administrative Council Minutes, 1934-1937 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Hospital Committee - Index, 1927-1937 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Hospital Committee, 1916-1927 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Hospital Committee, 1927-1929 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Hospital Committee, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Hospital Committee, 1930-1931 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Hospital Committee, 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Hospital Committee, 1932-1933 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Hospital Committee, 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Hospital Committee, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Hospital Committee, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Hospital Committee, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Library, 1918-1931 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Library, 1932-1936 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Library - Miscellaneous Chinese Volumes (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Medical Faculty - Index, 1921-1936 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Medical Faculty, 1920-1922 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Medical Faculty, 1922-1923 (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Medical Faculty, 1923-1924 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Medical Faculty, 1924-1925 (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Medical Faculty, 1925-1926 (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Medical Faculty, 1926-1927 (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Medical Faculty, 1927-1928 (Box 8, Folder 50)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Medical Faculty, 1928-1929 (Box 8, Folder 51)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Medical Faculty, 1929-1930 (Box 8, Folder 52)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Medical Faculty, 1930-1931 (Box 8, Folder 53)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Medical Faculty, 1931-1937 (Box 8, Folder 54)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Committee of Professors - Index, 1926-1937 (Box 8, Folder 55)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Committee of Professors, 1926-1930 (Box 8, Folder 56)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Committee of Professors, 1930-1934 (Box 8, Folder 57)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Committee of Professors, 1934-1937 (Box 9, Folder 58)
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Miscellaneous Committees (Box 9, Folder 59)
  Animal Room, 1921; Building, 1919-1920; Curriculum, 1921; Fellowships and Scholarship, 1921; Language Study, 1921; Peking American School, 1921; Pharmacy, 1921; Reprints, 1921; Special Committee on Student Grading, 1921; Special Committee on Student's Entrance Physical Exam, 1922; Technicians, 1922
- Administrative Council Committee Minutes - Miscellaneous Committees (Box 9, Folder 60)
  Admissions, 1921-1925; Advisory - School of Nursing, 1924; Budget, 1921-1925; Care and Use of Animals, 1924-1925; College Health Service, 1929; Contracts, 1922-1925; Housing, 1921-1926; Medical Students, 1925-1926; Pre-Medical and Medical Students, 1922-1925; Publications, 1925; Women Students, 1921-1922
- Advisory Committee, 1921-1928 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  Chuan; Director; Fan; Greene; Houghton; Tsai; Tsur
- Aid-American (C) (Box 9, Folder 62)
  Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals, 1952; Allocation of Space, 1929-1930 (Greene); Amberson, J. Burns, 1944; American Board of Commissioners, 1924, 1935 (Barton); American Board of Missionary Hospitals, 1923 (Tehchow-Tucker); American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, 1943-1947, 1969 (Bachman; Balfour; Co Tui; Kohlberg; Lau; Loo; Medical Education Committee; Memo; Robinson; Stevens; Van Slyke); American College of Physicians, 1946 (Loveland, E. R.); American College of Surgeons, 1948-1949 (Crowell, B. C.); American Cyanamid Company, 1945 (Gilchrist, H.)
- American (E-R) (Box 9, Folder 63)
  American Express Company, 1942-1949 (Bliss, S. N.); American Journal of Psychiatry, 1953; American Medical Association, 1921-1928, 1948-1956, 1966 (Anderson, D. G.; Directory; Houghton; Meleney; Sanger; Simmons); American Museum of Natural History, 1919, 1931 (Peter, W. W.; Pindar, George); American Red Cross, 1941-1942
- Anatomical Diagnoses - Index, 1916-1930 (Box 9, Folder 64)
- Anatomical Diagnoses - Autopsy Nos. 1-300 (Box 10, Folder 65)
- Anatomical Diagnoses - Autopsy Nos. 301-600 (Box 10, Folder 66)
- Anatomical Diagnoses - Autopsy Nos. 601-1000 (Box 10, Folder 67)
- Anatomy, 1918-1927, 1932, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 68)
  Appointments; Black; Cadavers; Collection; Director; Greene - visiting professors; Houghton; Pearce
- Anatomy - Staff - Black, Adena Nevitt (Mrs. Davidson Black), 1934-1941 (Box 11, Folder 69)
- Anatomy - Staff - Black, Adena Nevitt (Mrs. Davidson Black), 1942-1966 (Box 11, Folder 70)
- Anatomy - Staff - Black, Davidson, 1918-1929 (Box 11, Folder 71)
- Anatomy - Staff - Black, Davidson, 1930-1934 (Box 11, Folder 72)
- Anatomy - Staff - Black, Davidson, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 73)
- Anatomy - Staff - Black, Davidson, 1958-1964 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  Regarding the work of Dora Hood on a biography of Black.
- Anatomy - Staff (C-D) (Box 11, Folder 75)
  Chang, Chun, 1947-1949; Chang, Tso-kan, 1945-1950; Congdon, Edgar D., 1922-1926; Cowdry, E. V., 1917-1929, 1953, 1959-1960; Detwiller, Samuel R., 1920-1927, 1932
  Items of special note in this folder include a Report on Armistice Celebration (1917), found under the mark-up Anatomy - Staff - Cowdry.
- Anatomy - Staff - Fortuyn, A. B. Droogleever, 1925-1958 (Box 11, Folder 76)
  Items of special note in this folder include an undated photograph of Fortuyn and a Report of Vandalism and Destruction at Peking Union Medical College (May 26, 1942).
- Anatomy - Staff - (H-Sm) (Box 12, Folder 77)
  Hsieh, E. T., 1915-1917; Hsu, Tien-lu, 1940-1941, 1947, 1951; Kappers, C. U. Ariens, 1923-1927, 1934, 1945-1946; Ma, Wen-chao, 1921-1925, 1931, 1940-1941, 1945, 1966; Meng, Ting-hsiu, 1931; Pan, Ming-tzu, 1925, 1935, 1941, 1944; Sabin, Florence, 1922-1923; Smith, G. Elliot, 1930
- Anatomy - Staff - (St-Y) (Box 12, Folder 78)
  Stevenson, Paul H., 1920-1928, 1932, 1936-1941, 1963, 1971; Stone, Robert S., 1919-1922; Tsang, Yu-chuan, 1941, 1945; Von Bonin, Gerhardt; 1927-1932; Wen, I-Chuan, 1926-1929, 1934, 1938-1939; Wood-Jones, Frederick, 1932-1934; Yu, Shao-chi, 1945-1946, 1965
  Items of special note in this folder include an Insignia of the White Cravat with Red and Blue Borders of the Order of the Jade (April 15, 1937) and a diploma (June 12, 1937). Both items can be found under the mark-up Anatomy - Staff - Stevenson.
  Related Archival Materials note
  See also Box 162, Folder 1; Oversized Folder 69, Item 1
- And-App (Box 12, Folder 79)
  Andrus, William DeWitt, 1927-1929; Animal Farm/House, 1924-1926, 1934; Alexics, E., 1947; Application - Fellowship (Pan, Shih-yi, 1945-1949, 1954)
- Appointments - Correspondence, 1921-1932 (Box 12, Folder 80)
  Scope and Contents
  General; Belknap; Comptroller; Debevoise; Director; Eggleston; Emslie; Greene; Houghton; Loucks; Tsur
- Appointments - Correspondence, 1933-1937, 1942, 1947-1948 (Box 12, Folder 81)
- Appointments - Contract Forms, Minutes, Regulations, Difficulties, 1922-1947 (Box 12, Folder 82)
  Difficulties (Hill; Schoen; Tong)
- App-Arm (Box 12, Folder 83)
  Appropriations, 1920, 1941; Architectural Service Bureau, 1926-1935, 1943-1945, 1961 (Anner, Carl J., 1927-1930; Anner, Conrad W., 1927-1935, 1945, 1961; Bennett, Benjamin F., 1927, 1943; Hussey, Harry H., 1931-1932; Jewett, L. R., 1929; Leavitt, Ernest E., 1929; Mao, H. C., 1930; Resident Director, 1927; Stuart, Charles M., 1926, 1930; Thunder, Charles, 1928-1929, 1934); Armitage, J. Auriol, 1915, 1919-1923
  See also Box 162, Folder 2
- Army Medical College, 1935, 1942-1948 (Box 13, Folder 84)
  Cheung, Kin; Green; Li, Chen-pin (Lee); Tai, T. Y.
- Art-Atw (Box 13, Folder 85)
  Arthur Woo Fund, 1928-1932 (Comptroller; Greene; Woo); Associate Board for Christian Colleges in China, 1943-1947 (Evans, C. A.); Association of Affiliated Sino-Foreign Institutions, 1927 (Director); Atwater, Reginald M., 1919-1920, 1924
- Audit - Correspondence, 1927-1936 (Box 13, Folder 86)
  Bradfield; Comptroller; Myers; Squire & Co.
- Audit - Reports, 1922-1929 (Box 13, Folder 87)
- Audit - Reports, 1932-1950 (Box 13, Folder 88)
- Bacteriology, 1922-1933 (Box 13, Folder 89)
  Amoss; Clinical Lab; Director; Greene; Houghton
- Bacteriology - Appointments, 1927-1933 (Box 13, Folder 90)
  Cash; Greene; Zinsser
- Bacteriology - Staff (B-L) (Box 13, Folder 91)
  Bauer, Johannes, 1923-1931; Chang, Nai-chu, 1940-1941, 1948-1949; Chen, Hsing-mei, 1931; Chue, Chung-yue, 1930; Goodrich, L. C., 1925; Kurotchkin, Timothy J., 1927-1940, 1947-1949 (See also - Publications, Chinese Medical Journal); Li, Chen-pien, 1925 (See also - Publications, Chinese Medical Journal); Li, Tao, 1930
- Bacteriology - Staff - Lim, C. E., 1923-1926, 1931-1947, 1954-1966, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 92)
- Bacteriology - Staff (P-Ta) (Box 14, Folder 93)
  Pan, Sylvia F., 1950-1964; Tang, Fei-fang, 1924-1928; Tao, Shan-ming, 1927, 1941, 1946 (See also Publications, Chinese Medical Journal)
- Bacteriology - Staff - Ten Broeck, Carl, 1920-1927, 1933, 1946-1949, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder 94)
- Bacteriology - Staff (To-W) (Box 14, Folder 95)
  Tomcsik, Joseph, 1926-1927, 1946; Tung, Tsun, 1934-1935, 1940-1947, 1961, 1964; Wong, Dorothy Huie, 1925-1933, 1949-1956, 1962-1964; Wong, Samuel C., 1941-1946, 1956, 1965
- Bacteriology - Staff (Y-Z) (Box 14, Folder 96)
  Yen, Chun-hui, 1936-1940, 1945, 1949 (See also - Publications, Chinese Medical Journal); Young, Chun-chieh, 1931-1932; Zia, Samuel H., 1926-1940, 1945-1951 (See also - Publications, Chinese Medical Journal)
- Bal-Bin (Box 14, Folder 97)
  Ballou, Earle H., 1938, 1941-1948, 1959; Banister, Jessie C., 1926; Barchet, Lucy Harriet, 1923-1932, 1953-1958, 1966, 1969-1970; Bersohn, Malcolm, 1950, 1954-1955; Bethune Medical School, 1946; Bingham, Hiram, 1927
- Biochemistry, 1921, 1925-1933 (Box 14, Folder 98)
  Amoss; Director; Greene; Hasting; Houghton; Merrill-Palmer School; Resident Director; Rose; Taylor; Wu
- Biochemistry - Staff (A-F) (Box 14, Folder 99)
  Adolph, Katherine (Mrs. William H. Adolph), 1965; Adolph, William H., 1945-1951, 1954, 1958; Carruthers, Albert C., 1927, 1930-1933, 1941, 1957-1958; Chang, Chang-ying, 1934-1935; Chen, Chao-chi, 1924; Chen, Tung-tou, 1927, 1930-1937; Cheng, Lan-hua, 1928; Chou, Chi-yuan, 1938-1941, 1946; Chow, Bacon F., 1931-1938, 1947; Fu, Ying, 1929-1930
- Biochemistry - Staff (H-Wa) (Box 15, Folder 100)